## **Huey Jiuan Chong (Jo)**

#### Software Engineer

https://github.com/jogit82 https://www.linkedin.com/in/jochong82/

iochong82@gmail.com

Software engineer with a computer science degree and three years of professional experience in full software development lifecycle for web applications and desktop platform. Strong understanding of object-oriented programming, design patterns, full-stack development and agile methodology. Outside of coding, I like Crossfit and hiking.

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript, C#, TypeScript, Java, SQL

Databases: PostgreSQL, MongoDB, MySQL, Oracle, IBM DB2

Frameworks: Angular 4, Node.js, jQuery, Bootstrap, Ruby on Rails, .NET

Others: Git, HTML, CSS, Heroku, Express js, AJAX, AWS EB2 deployment and monitoring, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop

#### FORMAL EDUCATION

- Multimedia University(2001-2006) Bachelor's degree in Computer Science
- Infosys Global Education Center(2007) Campus Connect Program (J2EE/Java)
- General Assembly(2016) Web Development Immersive

#### PERSONAL PROJECTS

- qwk.io (Angular 4, Node.js, MongoDB, Bootstrap) Web app to create surveys using markdown
- · Text categorization software (Artificial Intelligence, C++) Software using neural networks to categorizes articles
- · Drinkmate (drink-m8.herokuapp.com/) (Ruby on Rails, PostgreSQL, OAuth) Web app to search for drink recipes
- · Fox.vet (https://mighty-lake-8559.herokuapp.com) (Node.js, PostgreSQL, OAuth) Web app for veterinary professionals to share medical cases
- · Jungle (jogit82.github.io/Jungle) (JavaScript, HTML, CSS) Web based board game similar to Stratego and Chess

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Vector International - Software Engineer (June 2006 to June 2007)

- Developed an employee timesheet web app with Apache, MySQLand PHP(WAMP). Employees can manage their time off and vacation requests.
   Admins can use this web application to look at employee's clock-in and clock-out time stamps (data comes from employee badge scans from a server)
- Designed touch screen interfaces with VB.Net which integrated between Windows Embedded System and Merten hardware. They were installed at home where users control Merten's smart devices such as switches, blinds, etc through the touch screens.

## DHL Asia Pacific - Software Engineer/Business Analyst (August 2007 to April 2008)

DHL Integration Solutions are online web services integration capabilities and provides DHL service availability, transit times, rates, shipment, courier pickup and shipment tracking for over 165 countries around the world.

- Technical documentation.
- Designed user interfaces according to the 8 Golden Rules of Interface Design. Made sure the interface design is consistent across the web app, visual feedbacks, status updates and error handling.
- · Built prototypes for web apps using Java J2EE technologies such as JDBC, EJB, JSP, Java Servlets and JMS.

# General Assembly(Student) - Full-stack Engineer (November 2015 to March 2016)

Refreshed and updated my technical skills by learning trending frameworks like Node.js, Express.js, AngularJS, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Ruby on Rails and common APIs such as IBM Watson API, Cloudinary API, OAuth 2.0 and so forth.

- REST API build and consumption.
- Multiple projects using MVC frameworks.

## **VOLUNTEERING EXPERIENCE**

- Open Seattle as a front end developer HTML, CSS, JavaScript
- Sports Techie Meetup Group + Seattle Sounders FC as a hackathon organizer
- Seattle Techstar Startup Week

## INFORMAL EDUCATION

- · Deep dive in Angular 4 with Max on Udemy
- · MEAN app from scratch with Max on Udemy
- · Contribute to my own tech blog that documents my learning journey with Angular 2 (alwaysbecoding.bold.io)